IMRAN HUSSAIN

Flat C 409 Rufi Paradise Gulistan e Johar block 18

Karachi.

Cell Phone: 0346-3815520 E-mail: imranhs1977@gmail.com

Skype ID: imranhs1977

Personal Summary

A result oriented professional with more than 13 years of experience in Sales & Marketing. Having an expert hand on team development, team retention, sound leader-ship skills to achieve organizational objectives through sound planning and implementation. An individual wrapped with Motivation, Enthusiasm, self-discipline, adoption, hunger to learn & pro-activeness.

Acquired sets of skills with experienced

- Team hiring, training, development & retention.
- Persuasive communication skills.
- Sharp skills of planning, leading, organizing, controlling, implementing & reevaluating of organizational objective.
- Developing an environment for team to perform best.
- Follow the basic rules & adopt the new marketing trends.

Professional Experience

Assistant Product Manager

March 2015 to Present

'PharmaFive'

Job description

- To develop marketing plan for assigned brands.
- Helping sales team for organizing CME, RTDs & ward presentation.
- Organizing product trainings & refresher for sales team.
- New product launching, managing brand oriented activities.
- Ensure execution of marketing plan through sales team.

Sales Manager Kenya

July 2013 to November 2014

'Pharmevo Pharmaceuticals'

Job Description

- Head of marketing & sales in Kenya.
- Plan & execute all the marketing & sales activities through team.



- Hiring, developing, training, retaining team.
- Execution of company plan to achieve set marketing & financial objectives.
- Managing all the distribution related issues including, re-ordering, PO generation, team salaries & expenses debit note.
- Registration process.
- Achieving company marketing & financial objectives.

Achievements

- Conduct large CMEs, Ward presentations in Kenya.
- Aireez (montelukast) 5th leading prescribing brand.
- Create identity of Pharmevo in doctor's community.
- Participated in cardiac & Physicians conference.
- Achieved mile stone of 20k USD.
- Produced growth over 300% with utter hard work and dedication.

Area Sales Manager

Pharmevo Pharmaceuticals	March 2010 to June 2013
Kaizen Pharmaceuticals	Oct 2009 to Feb 2010
Bio vista Neutraceuticals	Mar 2008 to Sep 2009
Hilton Pharmaceuticals	Mar 2007 to Feb 2008

Medical Sales Representative

Roche Pakistan Aug 2002 – FEB 2007

Training & Development

- Area Management planning training with Pharmevo.
- Completed *'Effective Situational leadership'* course with Hilton Pharmaceuticals.
- Completed 'Team management' course with Hilton Pharmaceuticals.
- Completed 'Managerial skills' course with Hilton Pharmaceuticals.
- Completed the vastly recognized '*Rep one*' course for medical sales representatives covering Probing & Effective communication skills at Roche Pharmaceuticals.

Achievements & Awards

- Best presenter award for situational leadership.
- Achieved the highest marks in the 'Managerial skills' course.
- Five Consecutive year's annual target Achiever at Roche Pakistan.
- Achieved 20 consecutive Quarter-targets at Roche.

Education

- MBA in Marketing from Preston University, Hyd. with a CGPA of 3.2 (2006-2007).
- Bachelor of Science from Islamia College Sukkur Shah Abdul Lateef University, Khairpur. (2003-2004).
- Intermediate from Comprehensive College, Hyd. (1994 –1995).
- Matriculation from Comprehensive School, Hyd. (1992 –1993).

Personal Details

Father's Name: Tahir Hussain
Date of Birth: 4th of February 1977
Mobile # PK: 0346-3815520

Marital Status: Married

NIC: 41304-2945529-7